A Guide to the Correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Dept. of Health Professions, 1977-2012
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Dept. of Health Professions, 1977-2012
The Library of Virginia
35730, 35970, 52894
7.7 cu. ft. (9 boxes)
Virginia. Dept. of Health Professions. Office of the Director.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred 18 February 1998 by the Dept. of Health Professions, Richmond, Va. 23230 [Acc. 35730].
Transferred 1 September 1998 by the Dept. of Health Professions, Richmond, Va. 23230 [Acc. 35970].
Transferred 19 November 2019 by the Dept. of Health Professions, Henrico, Va. 23233 [Acc. 52894].
Biographical Information
The Department of Health Regulatory Boards was created by an act passed by the General Assembly on March 31, 1977, to provide administrative services to the health regulatory boards of the state. In 1986, the Department of Health Regulatory Boards was renamed the Department of Health Professions.
Scope and Content
These records contain correspondence with other agencies, various boards, and the Secretary of Health and Human Resources, as well as with constituents. In addition to correspondence, the records may also include reports, agendas, manuals, memoranda, minutes, studies, speeches and legislative materials. This series documents administrative activities, establishment of policy and procedures, and major achievements of the agency.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Correspondence and subject files, 1980-1994 [Accession 35730]
Series II: Correspondence and subject files, 1977-1989 [Accession 35970]
Series III: Correspondence and subject files, 1996-2012 [Accession 52894]
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence and subject files [Acc. 35730], 1980-1994., Extent: 1 cu. ft. (1 box). (Box 1)
  - Annual performance agreement, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual financial statements, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Board members, 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Board of Nursing, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Secretary Cullum, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Deputy Secretary Oswalt, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Respiratory therapists, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Executive Policy memorandum, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Expense reimbursement policies, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Health, Dept. of, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Interagency agreement DHP and DSS, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Legislation fact sheets, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Legislative materials, Board of Nursing, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Legislative proposals, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Legislation recommendations to the Governor, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Memorandum and correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Memorandum and correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Memorandum and correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Memorandum and correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Memorandum and correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Memorandum and correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Memorandum, Nurse aides training, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Policy and procedures manual, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - State Police, Dept. of, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Virginia Board of Commerce, Agency rules, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series II: Correspondence and subject files [Acc. 35970], 1977-1989., Extent: .70 cu. ft. (2 boxes). (Box 1-2)
  - Conflict of Interest, State of Economic Interests, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Conflict of Interest, State of Economic Interests, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Conflict of Interest, State of Economic Interests, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Board of Optometry, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Board of Pharmacy, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Board of Professional Counselors, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Board of Psychology, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Board of Veterinary Medicine, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Board of Nursing, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Nursing Home Administrators, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Board of Medicine, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Organizational Research Project (Barbara S. Brown), 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Nursing Aides, Board of Nursing, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Regulation Review Committee, Position papers, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Commission on Health Regulatory Boards, Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - Virginia Commission on Health Regulatory Boards, Memorandum, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Management Staff Conference, Agenda, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Management Staff Conference, Agenda, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Management Staff Conference, Agenda, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Management Staff Conference, Agenda, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Management Staff Conference, Minutes, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Management Staff Conference, Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series III: Correspondence and subject files, [Accession 52894], 1996-2012., Extent: 6 cu. ft. (6 boxes). (Box 1-6)
  - Constituent correspondence, A-Y, 1996-1999 (Box 1-2)
  - Constituent correspondence, A-Y, 2000-2002 (Box 3)
  - Constituent correspondence, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Constituent correspondence, A-K, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Constituent correspondence, L-Z, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Constituent correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Constituent correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Constituent correspondence, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Constituent correspondence, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Constituent correspondence, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Constituent correspondence, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 6-9)
  - Constituent correspondence, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Constituent correspondence, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
  - Directors correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Directors correspondence, 1994-2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Directors correspondence, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Directors correspondence, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Directors correspondence, 2004-2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Directors correspondence, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 1994-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, Del. Winsome E. Sears, 2000-2003 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 2007-2008 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 2008-2009 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Delegates and Senators, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence with U.S. Senators, 1996-2010 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Memorandum, 1994-2010 (Box 6, Folder 21)